Guide to the Fidelis Zitterbart Manuscripts, 1868-1915 SC.1967.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- 10 Meditations: [Heft] I: for Quartett, July 31, 1869; violin 1 part (12 p.), violin 2 part (11 p.), viola part (11 p.), and violoncello part (12 p.) (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - 10 Meditations: [Heft] I - Parts: Violin 1, July 31, 1869
  - 10 Meditations: [Heft] I - Parts: Violin 2, July 31, 1869; 2.
  - 10 Meditations: [Heft] I - Parts: Viola, July 31, 1869; 3.
  - 10 Meditations: [Heft] I - Parts: Violoncello, July 31, 1869; 4.
- 10 Meditations: Heft II: [for Quartett], 1869?; violin 1 part (10 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 73, Folder 9)
  Undated. Possibly the same date of composition as Heft I? Location: New York.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft II - Parts: Violin 1, 1869?; 1.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft II - Parts: Violin 2, 1869?; 2.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft II - Parts: Viola, 1869?; 3.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft II - Parts: Violoncello, 1869?; 4.
- 10 Meditations: Heft III: [for Quartett], September 22, 1869; violin 1 part (10 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - 10 Meditations: Heft III - Parts: Violin 1, September 22, 1869; 1.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft III - Parts: Violin 2, September 22, 1869; 2.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft III - Parts: Viola, September 22, 1869; 3.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft III - Parts: Violoncello, September 22, 1869; 4.
- 10 Meditations: Heft IV: [for Quartett], 1869?; violin 1 part (9 p.), violin 2 part (9 p.), viola part (9 p.), and violoncello part (9 p.) (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - 10 Meditations: Heft IV - Parts: Violin 1, 1869?; 1.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft IV - Parts: Violin 2, 1869?; 2.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft IV - Parts: Viola, 1869?; 3.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft IV - Parts: Violoncello, 1869?; 4.
- 10 Meditations: Heft V: [for Quartett], January 8, 1870; violin 1 part (14 p.), violin 2 part (12 p.), viola part (12 p.), and violoncello part (12 p.) (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - 10 Meditations: Heft V - Parts: Violin 1, January 8, 1870; 1.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft V - Parts: Violin 2, January 8, 1870; 2.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft V - Parts: Viola, January 8, 1870; 3.
  - 10 Meditations: Heft V - Parts: Violoncello, January 8, 1870; 4.
- Meditation: [in A major: for string quartet], May 28, 1911; violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), violin 3 part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Meditation - Parts: Violin 1, May 28, 1911; 1.
  - Meditation - Parts: Violin 2, May 28, 1911; 2.
  - Meditation - Parts: Viola, May 28, 1911; 3.
  - Meditation - Parts: Violoncello, May 28, 1911; 4.
- Twilight Scenes: Quartettsätze: for 2 Violins, Viola and Violoncello, October 30, 1911; violin 1 part (7 p.), violin 2 part (8 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (8 p.) (Box 73, Folder 14)
  The number "142" written in pencil on cover.
  - Twilight Scenes - Parts: Violin 1, October 30, 1911; 1.
  - Twilight Scenes - Parts: Violin 2, October 30, 1911; 2.
  - Twilight Scenes - Parts: Viola, October 30, 1911; 3.
  - Twilight Scenes - Parts: Violoncello, October 30, 1911; 4.
- Schwannen-Suite: für Violine I, Violine 2, Viola und Violoncello, violin 1 part (6 p.), violin 2 part (6 p.), viola part (6 p.), and violoncello part (6 p.) (Box 73, Folder 15)
  The number "144" written in pencil on cover. Contents: 1. Praeludio -- 2. Gavotte (Sweet Marie) -- 3. Scherzando minuett -- 4. Legende -- 5. Schwannengesang -- 6. Quasi bolero-capriccio.
  - Schwannen-Suite - Parts: Violin 1
  - Schwannen-Suite - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Schwannen-Suite - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Schwannen-Suite - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Valse Fantastique: No. 1: [für Quartett], violin 1 part (10 p.), violin 2 part (10 p.), viola part (8 p.), and violoncello part (10 p.) (Box 73, Folder 16)
  The number "147" written in pencil on cover. Subtitle on caption: 1ster Satz. Location: New York?
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 1 - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 1 - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 1 - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 1 - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Valse Fantastique: No. 2: [für Quartett], violin 1 part (4 p.), violin 2 part (4 p.), viola part (4 p.), and violoncello part (4 p.) (Box 73, Folder 17)
  The number "146" written in pencil on cover. Subtitle on caption: Op. 87. Location: New York.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 2 - Parts: Violin 1, 1.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 2 - Parts: Violin 2, 2.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 2 - Parts: Viola, 3.
  - Valse Fantastique: No. 2 - Parts: Violoncello, 4.
- Twilight Musings: [no.] 1: [for string quartet], October 27, 1904; violin 1 part (2 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (2 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 73, Folder 18)
  The number "1" pasted in on parts.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 1 - Parts: Violin 1, October 27, 1904; 1.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 1 - Parts: Violin 2, October 27, 1904; 2.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 1 - Parts: Viola, October 27, 1904; 3.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 1 - Parts: Violoncello, October 27, 1904; 4.
- Twilight Musings: [no.] 2: [for string quartet], October 28, 1904; violin 1 part (2 p.), violin 2 part (2 p.), viola part (2 p.), and violoncello part (2 p.) (Box 73, Folder 19)
  The number "2" pasted in on parts.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 1, October 28, 1904; 1.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violin 2, October 28, 1904; 2.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 2 - Parts: Viola, October 28, 1904; 3.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 2 - Parts: Violoncello, October 28, 1904; 4.
- Twilight Musings: [no.] 3: [for string quartet], October 28, 1904; violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 73, Folder 20)
  The number "3" pasted in on parts.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violin 1, October 28, 1904; 1.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violin 2, October 28, 1904; 2.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 3 - Parts: Viola, October 28, 1904; 3.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 3 - Parts: Violoncello, October 28, 1904; 4.
- Twilight Musings: [no.] 4: [for string quartet], October 28, 1904; violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and violoncello part (1 p.) (Box 73, Folder 21)
  The number "4" pasted in on parts.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 4 - Parts: Violin 1, October 28, 1904; 1.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 4 - Parts: Violin 2, October 28, 1904; 2.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 4 - Parts: Viola, October 28, 1904; 3.
  - Twilight Musings: [no.] 4 - Parts: Violoncello, October 28, 1904; 4.
- Inspiration: for Oboe solo, Flute obligato and Piano, 1 score (3 p.) (Box 74, Folder 1)
  Illustrated cover: color picture of St. Cecilia at a keyboard with baby angels with caption "Inspiration" pasted in on cover.
- Inspiration: [orchestral version], 1 score (7 p.), flute obligato part (1 p.), oboe solo part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), cornet 1 part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), and bass part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 2)
  Originally for flute, oboe and piano.
  - Inspiration - Score, 1.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Flute obligato, 2.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Oboe solo, 3.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Cornet 1, 7.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Cornet 2, 8.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 9.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Violin 1, 11.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Violin 2, 12.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Viola, 13.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Violoncello, 14.
  - Inspiration - Parts: Bass, 15.
- Longing: Reverie: [in Bb major]: for Oboe solo, Flute, Clarionet, Horn, Bassoon and Piano, 1913; 1 score (7 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe solo part (1 p.), clarinet part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), horn part (1 p.), and piano part (3 p.) (Box 74, Folder 3)
  At head of title: To Mr. Albert de Busscher.
  - Longing: Reverie - Score, 1913; 1.
  - Longing: Reverie - Parts: Flute, 1913; 2.
  - Longing: Reverie - Parts: Oboe solo, 1913; 3.
  - Longing: Reverie - Parts: Clarinet, 1913; 4.
  - Longing: Reverie - Parts: Bassoon, 1913; 5.
  - Longing: Reverie - Parts: Horn, 1913; 6.
  - Longing: Reverie - Parts: Piano, 1913; 7.
- Meditation: [in Bb major]: für Solo Clarionette in B, 2 Hörner in F [and] Bariton oder Zug Posaune, March 25, 1887; clarinet in B part (1 p.), horn 1 part (1 p.), horn 2 part (1 p.), and bariton part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 4)
  "Or Faghott" written in pencil on t.p. following Zug Posaune. Part also indicates bass trombone as a substitute instrumentation. At head of title: An Oscar Alfred Zitterbart.
  - Meditation - Parts: Clarinet in B, March 25, 1887; 1.
  - Meditation - Parts: Horn 1, March 25, 1887; 2.
  - Meditation - Parts: Horn 2, March 25, 1887; 3.
  - Meditation - Parts: Bariton, March 25, 1887; 4.
- Song without Words: [no. 1: in Eb major: for] Oboe or Cornet in Bb [and] Piano, 1 score (2 p.), oboe part (1 p.), and cornet part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Song without Words - Score, 1.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Oboe, 2.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Cornet, 3.
- Song without Words: No. 2: in Ab Major: [for] Oboe and Piano, 1 score (3 p.), and oboe part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Song without Words: No. 2 - Score, 1.
  - Song without Words: No. 2 - Oboe, 2.
- Song without Words: [in A major: for] Oboe and Piano, 1 score (2 p.), and oboe part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Song without Words - Score, 1.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Oboe, 2.
- Lied ohne Worte: [in Eb major]: für Oboe und Pianoforte, May 27, 1870; 1 score (4 p.), and oboe part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 8)
  "Opus 22" written in red ink on cover. On cover: Meimem Freunde Emil Tittel zum freundlichen Angedenken. Location: New York.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Score, May 27, 1870; 1.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Oboe, May 27, 1870; 2.
- The Jelgerhouse Cantabile: in Eb Major: for Oboe and Piano, November 18, 1895; 1 score (3 p.), and oboe part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 9)
  At head of title: To Mr. J.V. Jelgerhouse respectfully.
  - The Jelgerhouse Cantabile - Score, November 18, 1895; 1.
  - The Jelgerhouse Cantabile - Parts: Oboe, November 18, 1895; 2.
- Introductione et Adagio Cantabile: [in Eb major]: for Oboe and Piano, July 4, 1908; 1 score (7 p.), and oboe part (2 p.) (Box 74, Folder 10)
  Illustrated cover: Yellow, floral border pasted in around title and composer's name.
  - Introductione et Adagio Cantabile - Score, July 4, 1908; 1.
  - Introductione et Adagio Cantabile - Parts: Oboe, July 4, 1908; 2.
- Romanza: in F Major: for Oboe and Piano, July 31, 1915; 1 score (5 p.), and oboe part (2 p.) (Box 74, Folder 11)
  At head of title: To Mr. J.V. Jelgerhouse. Location: Erie, Pa.
  - Romanza: in F Major - Score, July 31, 1915; 1.
  - Romanza: in F Major - Parts: Oboe, July 31, 1915; 2.
- Dedication: [in Ab major: for] Oboe and Piano, 1 score (2 p.), and oboe part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - Dedication - Score, 1.
  - Dedication - Parts: Oboe, 2.
- Theme and Variations: [in Bb major]: for Clarionet with Piano accompaniment, August 25, 1887; 1 score (8 p.), and clarinet in B part (3 p.) (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - Theme and Variations - Score, 1.
  - Theme and Variations - Clarinet, 2.
- Paul and Virgina: Duo Romantique: [in Bb major]: for Violin and Clarionet in Bb with Piano accompaniment, November 15, 1911; 1 score (11 p.), clarinet part (3 p.), violin part (3 p.), and violin 2 part (3 p.) (Box 74, Folder 14)
  At head of title: Written expressly for Mr. and Mrs. John E. St. Clair. The violin II part is the clarinet part transposed.
  - Paul and Virgina: Duo Romantique - Score, November 15, 1911; 1.
  - Paul and Virgina: Duo Romantique - Parts: Clarinet, November 15, 1911; 2.
  - Paul and Virgina: Duo Romantique - Parts: Violin 1, November 15, 1911; 3.
  - Paul and Virgina: Duo Romantique - Parts: Violin 2, November 15, 1911; 4.
- Lied ohne Worte: [in F major]: Cornet solo avec accompagnement de Quartett, May 27, 1891; 1 score (2 p.), solo cornet in B part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (2 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), and bass part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 15)
  Score in oblong format written in pencil. Title on wrapper: Song without words.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Score, May 27, 1891; 1.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Solo Cornet in B, May 27, 1891; 2.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violin 1, May 27, 1891; 3.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violin 2, May 27, 1891; 4.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Viola, May 27, 1891; 5.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violoncello, May 27, 1891; 6.
  - Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Bass, May 27, 1891; 7.
- With Thee: Song without Words: [in Eb major: for] Cornet solo [and] Piano, 1 score (2 p.), and cornet part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 16)
  - With Thee: Song without Words - Score, 1.
  - With Thee: Song without Words - Parts: Cornet, 2.
- Mates: Duett for Cornet and Trombone: with Orchestral accompagnement, 1 score (6 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), solo cornet part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (1 p.), solo trombone part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), and piano part (2 p.) (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Mates - Score, 1.
  - Mates - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Mates - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Mates - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - Mates - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - Mates - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Mates - Parts: Solo Cornet, 7.
  - Mates - Parts: Cornet 2, 8.
  - Mates - Parts: Horns 1 and 2, 9.
  - Mates - Parts: Solo Trombone, 10.
  - Mates - Parts: Trombone, 11.
  - Mates - Parts: Violin 1, 12.
  - Mates - Parts: Violin 2, 13.
  - Mates - Parts: Viola, 14.
  - Mates - Parts: Violoncello, 15.
  - Mates - Parts: Bass, 16.
  - Mates - Parts: Piano, 17.
- Song without Words: [in Ab major]: for Cornet solo in Bb with Orchestral accompagnement, 1 score (5 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), and bass part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 18)
  Incomplete; lacks parts for solo cornet, 2 clarinets in Bb, bassoon, cornet II in Bb, 2 horns in F, trombone and piano.
  - Song without Words - Score, 1.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Violin 1, 4.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Violin 2, 5.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Viola, 6.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Violoncello, 7.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Bass, 8.
- Song without Words: [in Bb major]: Duett for Cornet in Bb and Trombone with Orchestral accompagnement, 1 score (6 p.), flute part (1 p.), oboe part (1 p.), clarinet 1 part (1 p.), clarinet 2 part (1 p.), bassoon part (1 p.), horn 1 and 2 part (1 p.), solo cornet part (1 p.), cornet 2 part (1 p.), trombone part (1 p.), violin 1 part (2 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), violoncello part (1 p.), bass part (1 p.), and piano part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Song without Words - Score, 1.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Flute, 2.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Oboe, 3.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Clarinet 1, 4.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Clarinet 2, 5.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Bassoon, 6.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Horn 1 and 2, 7.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Solo Cornet, 8.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Cornet 2, 9.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Trombone, 10.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Violin 1, 11.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Violin 2, 12.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Viola, 13.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Violoncello, 14.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Bass, 15.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Piano, 16.
- Song without Words: [in Eb major]: for Cornet solo and Piano accompagnement, 1 score (1 p.), and cornet solo part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - Song without Words - Score, 1.
  - Song without Words - Parts: Cornet Solo, 2.
- Ein Lied ohne Worte: [in E major]: für Cornet Solo: mit Begleitung von Violine I, Violine II, Viola, Cello et Basso, Flute et Clarionette, 1872; flute part (1 p.), clarinet in A part (1 p.), trumpet in A part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), viola part (1 p.), and cello and bass part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 21)
  Incomplete; lacks part for solo cornet, and possibly others? Location: Sharon Springs, [NY].
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Flute, 1872; 1.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Clarinet in A, 1872; 2.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Trumpet in A, 1872; 3.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violin 1, 1872; 4.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violin 2, 1872; 5.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Viola, 1872; 6.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Cello and Bass, 1872; 7.
- Ein Lied ohne Worte, 1872?; violin 1 part (3 copies, each 1 p.), violin 2 part (3 copies, each 1 p.), viola part (2 copies, each 1 p.), and cello part (1 p.) (Box 74, Folder 22)
  Incomplete; string parts only. Larger size (35 cm).
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violin 1, 1872?; 1.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Violin 2, 1872?; 2.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Viola, 1872?; 3.
  - Ein Lied ohne Worte - Parts: Cello, 1872?; 4.
- Nearer my God to Thee: Hymn: for Flute, 2 Violins and Piano, May 21, 1888; flute part (1 p.), violin 1 part (1 p.), violin 2 part (1 p.), and piano part (2 p.) (Box 74, Folder 23)
  At head of title (but crossed out in pencil): Dedicated and written expressly for the M. Church congregation. At bottom of t.p. (also crossed out in pencil): The congregation will please rise and sing the hymn along with the instrumentalists.
  - Nearer my God to Thee - Parts: Flute, May 21, 1888; 1.
  - Nearer my God to Thee - Parts: Violin 1, May 21, 1888; 2.
  - Nearer my God to Thee - Parts: Violin 2, May 21, 1888; 3.
  - Nearer my God to Thee - Parts: Piano, May 21, 1888; 4.
- Faust: 3 Characterbilder: für Orchester, September 20, 1892; 1 score (31 p.) (Box 75, Folder 1)
  Score is in oblong format and written in pencil. Subtitle on cover: Characterstücke. Contents: 1. Dr. Faust -- 2. Margaretha -- 3. Mephisto.
- Faust: Characterstücke: für Orchester, September 20, 1892; 1 score (38 p.), picolo part (2 p.), flute 1 part (4 p.), flute 2 part (3 p.), clarinet 1 in B part (4 p.), clarinet 2 in B part (3 p.), 2 oboes part (3 p.), 2 horns part (4 p.), 2 cornets in B part (3 p.), trombone part (3 p.), cymbal part (1 p.), violin 1 part (3 copies, each 5 p.), violin 2 part (3 copies, each 4 p.), viola part (4 p.), viola part (4 p.), violoncello principale part (4 p.), violoncello 1 part (4 p.), violoncello 2 part (4 p.), and bass part (4 p.) (Box 75, Folder 2)
  Contents: 1. Faust -- 2. Marguerite -- 3. Mephistopholes.
  - Faust - Score, September 20, 1892; 1.
  - Faust - Parts: Picolo, September 20, 1892; 2.
  - Faust - Parts: Flute 1, September 20, 1892; 3.
  - Faust - Parts: Flute 2, September 20, 1892; 4.
  - Faust - Parts: Clarinet 1 in B, September 20, 1892; 5.
  - Faust - Parts: Clarinet 2 in B, September 20, 1892; 6.
  - Faust - Parts: 2 Oboes, September 20, 1892; 7.
  - Faust - Parts: 2 Horns, September 20, 1892; 8.
  - Faust - Parts: 2 Cornets in B, September 20, 1892; 9.
  - Faust - Parts: Trombone, September 20, 1892; 10.
  - Faust - Parts: Cymbal, September 20, 1892; 11.
  - Faust - Parts: Violin 1, September 20, 1892; 12.
  - Faust - Parts: Violin 2, September 20, 1892; 13.
  - Faust - Parts: Viola, September 20, 1892; 14.
  - Faust - Parts: Violoncello Principal, September 20, 1892; 15.
  - Faust - Parts: Violoncello 1, September 20, 1892; 16.
  - Faust - Parts: Violoncello 2, September 20, 1892; 17.
  - Faust - Parts: Bass, September 20, 1892; 18.
- Faust: Characterstücke: für Orchester, September 20, 1892; 1 score (38 p.), piccolo part (2 p.), flute 1 part (4 p.), flute 2 part (4 p.), clarinet 1 in B part (4 p.), clarinet 2 in B part (3 p.), 2 oboes part (3 p.), 2 horns part (4 p.), 2 cornets in B part (3 p.), trombone part (3 p.), cymbal part (1 p.), violin 1 and solo part (5 p.), violin 1 part (5 p.), violin 2 part (2 copies, each 4 p.), viola part (4 p.), cello principle part (4 p.), cello 1 part (4 p.), cello 2 part (4 p.), and bass part (4 p.) (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Faust - Score, September 20, 1892; 1.
  - Faust - Parts: Piccolo, September 20, 1892; 2.
  - Faust - Parts: Flute 1, September 20, 1892; 3.
  - Faust - Parts: Flute 2, September 20, 1892; 4.
  - Faust - Parts: Clarinet 1 in B, September 20, 1892; 5.
  - Faust - Parts: Clarinet 2 in B, September 20, 1892; 6.
  - Faust - Parts: 2 Oboes, September 20, 1892; 7.
  - Faust - Parts: 2 Horns, September 20, 1892; 8.
  - Faust - Parts: 2 Cornets in B, September 20, 1892; 9.
  - Faust - Parts: Trombone, September 20, 1892; 10.
  - Faust - Parts: Cymbal, September 20, 1892; 11.
  - Faust - Parts: Violin 1 and Solo, September 20, 1892; 12.
  - Faust - Parts: Violin 1, September 20, 1892; 13.
  - Faust - Parts: Violin 2, September 20, 1892; 14.
  - Faust - Parts: Viola, September 20, 1892; 15.
  - Faust - Parts: Cello Principal, September 20, 1892; 16.
  - Faust - Parts: Cello 1, September 20, 1892; 17.
  - Faust - Parts: Cello 2, September 20, 1892; 18.
  - Faust - Parts: Bass, September 20, 1892; 19.
- Ouverture: Iago: for Orchestra, November 23, 1892; 1 score (32 p.), flute 1 part (3 p.), flute 2 part (3 p.), oboe part (3 p.), clarinet 1 part (3 p.), clarinet 2 part (3 p.), bassoon part (3 p.), horn 1 part (2 p.), horn 2 part (3 p.), cornet 1 part (3 p.), cornet 2 part (3 p.), trombone part (3 p.), timpani part (2 p.), violin 1 part (4 copies, 3, 4, 4 and 4 p.), violin 2 part (3 copies, each 3 p.), viola part (2 copies, each 3 p.), violoncello part (2 copies, each 4 p.), and bass part (3 p.) (Box 75, Folder 4)
  Tape on score edges.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Score, November 23, 1892; 1.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Flute 1, November 23, 1892; 2.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Flute 2, November 23, 1892; 3.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Oboe, November 23, 1892; 4.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Clarinet 1, November 23, 1892; 5.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Clarinet 2, November 23, 1892; 6.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: 2 Bassoons, November 23, 1892; 7.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Horn 1, November 23, 1892; 8.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Horn 2, November 23, 1892; 9.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Cornet 1, November 23, 1892; 10.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Cornet 2, November 23, 1892; 11.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Trombone, November 23, 1892; 12.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Timpani, November 23, 1892; 13.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Violin 1, November 23, 1892; 14.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Violin 2, November 23, 1892; 15.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Viola, November 23, 1892; 16.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Violoncello, November 23, 1892; 17.
  - Ouverture: Iago - Parts: Bass, November 23, 1892; 18.
- Ouverture: in F Major: The Merry Princess: für Orchestra, May 7, 1888; 1 score (17 p.), flute part (3 p.), oboe part (2 p.), clarinet 1 in B part (3 p.), clarinet 2 in B part (3 p.), bassoon part (2 p.), horn 1 part (2 p.), horn 2 part (2 p.), cornet 1 in B part (2 p.), cornet 2 in B part (2 p.), trombone part (2 p.), timpani part (2 p.), violin 1 part (3 copies, each 3 p.), violin 2 part (3 copies, each 3 p.), viola part (3 p.), violoncello part (3 p.), bass part (3 p.), and piano part (4 p.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
  Score in oblong format. Parts in upright format and dated 6/9/1888. The word "juvenile" on t.p. of score and parts is crossed out.
  - Ouverture: in F Major - Score, May 7, 1888; 1.